两大种族出现已过了二十年
Two decades had passed since the creation of both species.
战争早已展开
The war had begun.
维克多壮大他的军队 创造吸血鬼军团
Viktor increased his army, creating a legion of vampires
来保护他们 免受第一氏狼族的攻击
to protect them from the very first clan of werewolves:
这个邪恶又有传染性的物种 永远无法转换成人形
A vicious and infectious breed unable to take human form ever again.
直到他出世
Until he was born.
卢西恩
Lucian.
虽然维克多身上的每个细胞 都警告他要处决这个孩子
And although every fiber of Viktor's soul warned him to slay this child,
但他没有
he did not.
过了许多年 这孩子长大了
Over the years, this child grew.
他拥有先前那个物种所没有的 力量和专注力
He possessed a strength and focus that the ones before him did not.
你觉得呢 索妮亚？
What do you think, Sonja?
我们该多制造一些吗？
Shall we make more?
制造他？
Of him?
像他一样的东西
Like him.
卢西恩永远都会是狼人族的始祖
Lucian will always be the first of the breed,
第一个狼人
the first of the Lycans.
维克多利用卢西恩具有传染性的血
Viktor would use Lucian's infectious blood to his benefit,
利用这孩子的饥渴
taking advantage of the child's thirst,
逼迫他以人类为食
pitting it against him as he was forced to feed on humans,
也就是维克多的奴隶
Viktor's slaves.
- 进去! - 进里面去
- Get in there. - In there.
他创造了一个新的不死种族
Instead, he created a new race of immortals:
狼人
Lycans.
是狼也是人
Werewolf, but also human.
不同的是 这个新种族可以被利用
Unlike the others, this new breed could be harnessed,
作为在白昼守护他们主人的奴隶
enslaved to guard them in the daylight hours of their masters.
或者维克多是这么盘算的
Or so Viktor thought
那是在很久以前
so very long ago.
《黑夜传说3：狼族再起》
贵族们很失望 大人
The nobles are upset, my lord.
威廉的传染病并未停止
William's pestilence has not been checked.
- 狼人们杀了他们的奴隶 - 人类很沮丧
- Werewolves have killed their slaves. - Humans upset.
坦尼斯 记下我对这点感到很难过
Tannis, please take a note of what pain that brings me.
他们没了奴隶代表我们没了银子
Yet their lost slaves means our lost silver.
够了!  我不是增加了十倍的收入？
Enough. Have I not increased our holdings tenfold
自从马库斯和阿米莉亚冬眠后
since Marcus and Amelia took their sleep?
我们会照常对付狼族
We will deal with the wolves as we always have.
- 快点! - 快啊!
- Come on! - Come on, quickly!
射击!
Fire!
关上大门
Close that breach.
铁匠 你除了玩武器之外
Have you nothing better to do, blacksmith,
没别的事好做了吗？
than play with weapons of war?
做点有用的事吧
At least make yourself useful.
对救命恩人要心存感激 索妮亚
A little gratitude, Sonja, to the one who saved your life.
我并不需要人救
I needed no saving.
告诉我 卢西恩
Tell me, Lucian.
杀死自己的同类会令你感到难过吗？
Does it burden your heart to kill your own kind?
不会 它们只是野兽 主人
Not at all. They're mindless beasts, my lord.
- 不是我的伙伴 - 真的？
- No brethren of mine. - Really?
父亲
Father.
你是你们族人的骄傲 你知道接下来该怎么做吧？
You are a credit to your race. Do you know how to remain so?
目光别离开地面
Keep your eyes on the ground.
把那个处理掉
Get rid of that.
你真让理事会难堪
You were sorely missed at council.
我还有其他事要忙
There are other demands on my time, as you know.
是啊 希望你享受月下散步
I see. I hope you enjoyed your little moonlit ride.
我是去巡逻
I was out patrolling.
你根本是抗命 我说过要你待在城墙之内
You were disobeying. I told you to stay within these walls.
我这个做父亲的不能再任你挺而走险了
You risk too much for a father to ignore.
把狼族交给死亡行者处理
You will leave the wolves to the Death Dealers.
为什么？我冒的险又不比他们大
And why, Father, is my risk any greater than theirs?
他们不是我女儿
They are not my daughters,
也不是理事会成员 但你是
and they are not council members. You are.
有一天 你会继承我成为长老
And one day, you will become an elder, your birthright.
索妮亚 理事会很体谅你
Sonja, you are well thought of at council,
不过那么做太危险了
but that is a precarious thing.
他们开始厌烦你的游戏和缺席
They grow tired of your games and your absences.
森林里潜藏的危险并不比议会厅里多
The dangers of the forest are no greater than those of the council chamber.
你要学会舞弄政治 学会冷酷又狡猾
You will learn the dance of politics, to be ruthless and cunning.
更重要的是 你要对家族忠诚
And above all, you will be loyal to your family.
对我忠诚
To me.
毕竟 我们之间若没有忠诚
After all, without the loyalty between us,
就与门口那些野兽无异
we are no better than the beasts at our door.
给我继续做
Put your back into it.
捡起来
Pick that up.
快点 废物
Move it, you scum.
多一点
More spin.
起来
Get up.
狼人
Lycan.
不准休息 快工作!
No rest, dog.
够了
Enough.
你竟敢反抗我？
You dare raise your hand to me?
- 我说够了 - 当主子的狗就能大声啦？
- I said, that's enough. - So says the master's dog, hm?
你不会永远受他宠爱的 当你失宠时
You will not always be his favorite, and when you fall,
我必会在场观看
I will be there.
等着瞧吧
Let us hope so.
你们看什么？ 马上回去工作!
What are you looking at? Get back to work now!
回去工作!
Get back to work!
Back to work.
理事会眼前的议题很简单
The matter before the council is simple.
我们正遭受攻击
We are under attack.
这些日子以来有许多次
Six times in half as many weeks,
狼族都攻到了我们墙边
William's kind have reached our very walls.
若被攻破将会出现何等混乱？
What mayhem would follow ifjust one of them got through?
你的恐惧 科洛曼 是无谓的
Your fear, Coloman, is misplaced.
不是有支不死大军护卫我们吗？
Are we not protected by an army of immortals?
是啊 大人
Superbly, my lord.
然而贵族们并不觉得…
However, the nobles are not, and as I have pointed out,
我说过 他们是我们的财富来源
they are the grass on which we graze.
我们若无法保护人类 就表示我们的衰弱
If we cannot protect our humans, it makes us look weak.
那么你们要如何展现力量？
And how would you project strength?
夜里由我们的死亡行者巡逻
As our Death Dealers patrol the night,
白天则由我们的白昼门卫巡逻
so our daylight guards can patrol the day.
狼人去城外巡逻？
Lycans patrol outside the walls?
你是不是疯了？
Have you lost your mind?
他们是野兽的后代
They are born of beasts,
这可悲的事实不会消失的
and the savagery of this despicable fact cannot be bred away.
我想你对这想法的惧怕是无谓的
I think your fear of this idea is misplaced.
我们可以创造一群特级的狼人
We can create a privileged class of Lycans.
提供更好的粮食、宿舍 让他们接受我们信赖的人来统领
Greater rations, finer quarters, and put them under the hand of one we trust.
也许就是你的宠物 卢西恩
Perhaps your pet, Lucian.
今天救了你女儿一命的那个家伙
The one who saved your daughter's life today.
事实上 我想该听听她的想法
In fact, I think we should hear her thoughts on this matter.
她似乎在忙别的事
She seems to have been needed elsewhere.
去找她
Find her.
我会将你的建议纳入考虑
I will take your suggestion under advisement.
谢谢您 大人
Thank you, my lord.
在明天贵族们抵达时 能向他们重申我们对他们的关切
It would be gratifying to be able to reassure the nobles
将会是件令人高兴的事
when they arrive tomorrow that we have their interests at heart.
- 快点! - 动作快!
- Move it! -  Move it!
继续 懒猪
Go on, slowpoke.
去哪里
Over there. There.
- 快啊! - 别慢下来 继续走
- Move it! - Don't go slow. Keep going.
动作快!
Move it along!
小姐？
My lady?
那是真的吗？你跟我父亲说…
Is it true what you told my father,
你杀它们的时候毫无感觉
that you feel nothing when you kill them?
它们只是野兽
They're just animals,
完全不会思考或感受
incapable of thought or feeling,
我为什么要对它们有感觉？
so why should I feel anything for them?
索妮亚 如果我要离开这里 你愿意跟我走吗？
Sonja, if I were to leave from here, would you come with me?
离开？
Leave?
别提那个字眼
Do not say that.
连想都别想 他们会猎杀你
Do not even think it. They would hunt you down
- 把你当野兽 - 若我能拿掉这个就不一定了
- and they would mark you like all the others. - Not if I could remove this.
你看
Look.
我做的
I made it.
这是我的自由
This will be my freedom.
卢西恩 答应我你不会用它
Lucian, promise me you won't use it.
- 拜托 - 那么这就是你的答案了？
- Please. - Is that your answer, then?
你不会跟我走
You will not come.
你要我为你留下？
So you want me to stay here for you?
- 像这样？像动物一样？- 卢西恩
- Like this, like an animal? - Lucian.
吸血鬼和狼人 我们都是柯文纳斯的子孙
Vampire and Lycan, we are both children of Corvinus,
然而我的族人却是奴隶
yet my family are slaves.
我会用这把钥匙
I will use this key,
我也会离开此地
and I will leave this place,
不过没有你我不会走
but I can never be without you now.
- 有我女儿的消息吗？- 她很叛逆
- Any news of my daughter? - She's most defiant.
她拒绝见我
She refuses to see me.
- 也不肯应门 - 年轻人怎么都这么盲目？
- Will not answer her door. - Why are the young so blind?
她会丧失理事会席位 为了什么？
She risks her seat on the council, and for what?
我无法想像
I cannot imagine.
我们得准备了 大人
We must prepare, my lord.
人类贵族已经上路了
Human nobles are on their way.
它很锋利 必能劈死恶狼
It's sharp. No wolf will stand before it.
备马
Ready the horses.
让别人去吧
Let someone else go.
- 为什么？- 昨晚 我和你分手之后…
- Why? - Last night, after I left you...
让别人去吧
Just let someone else go.
你可能没注意到 铁匠
In case it had escaped your notice, blacksmith,
我很有能力照顾自己
I am quite capable of looking after myself.
还有
And besides,
你可以从城墙上看着我
you can watch over me from the wall.
回去后面
Get your back to the rear.
索妮亚小姐 您父亲下令要您留下
Lady Sonja, your father has ordered you to stay behind.
我想亲自护送我们的客人
I intend to see our guests safely through the gate.
- 守门人 - 这不是请求
- Gate master. - This is not a request.
您父亲是我们的领袖
Your father is ruler of the coven.
他也一直提醒我这一点
So he keeps reminding me.
回去!
Get back!
注意点 铁匠
Careful, blacksmith,
别让你的眼神泄露秘密
lest your eyes betray your secret.
稳住 稳住
Steady. Steady.
关上窗 孩子
Shut it, my child. Shut it.
准备迎击!
Form up!
不
No.
快让你的手下出去
Get your men out there now!
冷静点 你太激动了
Down, boy. Your leash is too tight.
- 稳住! - 它们太多了
- Step away. - There's too many of them.
这会是一场屠杀
They'll be massacred.
阻止他!
Stop him!
骑出去…
Ride out. Ride out.
小心
Easy.
迪米特里!
Dimitri.
卢西恩!
Lucian!
索妮亚!
Sonja!
卢西恩 不!
Lucian, no.
不! 住手!
No, stop!
他是为了救我
He did it to save me.
我不是主人了吗？
Am I not master of this house?
你知道颈圈是绝对不能取下的
You know you are forbidden to remove your shackle.
是的
Yes.
我赐你新生 你却抗命
Yet you break my law after I gave you your life.
你舒适的生活结束了 奴隶
Your days of plush living are over, slave.
父亲 放了他
Father, leave him be.
- 我说过… - 给我住嘴
- I told you... - Hold your tongue!
这是你最后一次违抗我的命令
You have defied me for the last time.
把她带走
Get her out of here.
烧了尸体
Burn the bodies.
全都烧掉
Burn them all.
因为拿掉颈圈…
For removing the collar,
三十鞭
30 lashes.
你的背叛令我难过 狼人
You have stung me, Lycan, with your betrayal.
你原本就像是我的儿子一样
You were like a son to me.
我给了你生命
I gave you your life.
你却给我枷锁
You gave me chains.
我早该想到 经过这些年 你早该学会
I would have thought, after all these years, you would have known
你毕竟得跟你的同类在一起
you cannot have one without the other.
动手吧
Do it.
我说过你失宠时我必会在场
I told you I'd be there when you fell.
- 怎么？- 停手吧
- What? - Stop this.
- 他是我们的护卫 - 他们只是野兽
- He is one of our protectors. - They are but beasts themselves.
- 这可能会激怒其他狼人 - 随便他们 你怕他们？
- This could stir up the others. - Let them stir. Do you fear them?
相信我 不惩罚结果只会更糟
Believe me, it will be worse if we do not punish them.
你以为在城外能信任他们？
Do you see now, Coloman? You would trust them
他们连在城内都信不过了
outside the walls? We cannot even trust them inside.
照我计算 那是第二十一鞭
By my count, that's 21.
继续
Continue.
好可怕的声音
Oh, what a terrible sound.
臭死了
Bloody stink.
离他远点 不然他们也会惩罚你
Stay away from him, or they'll punish you too.
你对卢西恩的关心真令人感动
Your concern for Lucian was most touching.
一个奴隶
A slave.
他刚刚救了我一命
He had just saved my life.
你之前不是叫我要心存感激？
Was it not you who told me to show a little gratitude?
那你自己呢？
And yourself?
你不感谢救你女儿一命的人？
Have you no gratitude for the one who saved your daughter's life?
我感激涕零
I am awash with it.
他能活命显示我的宽容大量
That he lives shows the breadth of my magnanimity.
换做别的情况
Were it any other circumstances,
我早把他扔去 给他自己的族人分食
I would have had him fed in pieces to his own kind.
不过他的惩罚现在已经结束了
But his punishment is now over.
- 你会释放他吧？ - 释放？
- He will be freed. - Freed?
你的判断有点迟钝
Your judgment is clouded, Sonja.
我们不是用情感来保持秩序的
We do not keep order with sentiment.
卢西恩拿掉他不准拿掉的颈圈
Lucian was forbidden to remove his collar, and yet he did so,
不论理由有多好
for however fine a reason.
他都得留在牢里
He will remain in prison,
用以告诫他人
a cautionary tale.
亚诺士和其他贵族即将抵达
Janosh and the other nobles will soon arrive.
你的出席是必要的
Your presence is expected.
我看到你的身手
I saw what you did out there.
很勇猛
Very brave
对一个人类而言
for a human.
你之前遭遇过它们吗？
Have you come across them before?
完全没有
Only in stories.
你不怕它们？
Were you not afraid of them?
怕
Yes,
不过我想活命
but I wanted to live.
你怕我吗？
Are you afraid of me?
- 怕 - 不用怕
- Yes. - Well, do not be.
我不咬人
I will not bite...
不大咬
much.
- 你跟它们一样？- 不
- You are like them? - No.
我是狼人 但跟它们不一样
A Lycan, yes, but not like them.
你今晚对抗的是野兽 是威廉的子孙
Those you fought with tonight were animals, the spawn of William.
血统纯正 完全没有人类的基因
Purebloods, if you will. No trace of human left.
野蛮、无知的野兽
Savage, mindless beasts.
- 和传说一样 - 不过我看到你
- As it has been told. - But I saw you.
它们听你的
They obeyed you.
是的
Yes.
对 没错
Yes, they did.
嘿
Hey.
- 你不该来此 - 我必须来
- Oh, you should not be here. - I had to.
亲爱的 对不起
My love, I'm sorry.
- 你的背 - 我没事
- Your back. No, no, - I'm all right.
是我的错 要是我没出去…
This is my fault. If I had not gone out...
那你就不是你了
Then you would not be who you are.
这不是你的错
This is not your fault.
我不能留在这里 我得离开
I cannot remain here. I have to leave this place.
我父亲现在会更严加监控你
My father will be watching you now more than ever.
死亡行者呢？里面没你的亲信？
What about your Death Dealers, are there none that you can trust?
他们对我父亲比对我忠心
Unfortunately, their loyalty to my father is greater than their loyalty to me.
坦尼斯
Tannis.
- 不能相信他 - 不 他知道我们的事
- Tannis cannot be trusted. - No, Tannis, he knows about us.
- 怎么会？- 我不知道
- How? - I have no idea.
若他还没告诉你父亲 那就有鬼
But if he still has not told your father, then that must mean he wants something.
去查他在打什么算盘
Sonja, find out what it is.
带他们进来
Bring them in.
亚诺士
Janosh.
你不是拥有最大的银矿吗？
Do you not own the largest silver mine in these lands?
已经都荒废了 大人
It has been overrun, my lord.
工人都受到感染
Our workers infected,
变成野兽
turned to beasts.
真不幸
Most unfortunate,
牺牲真大
and costly.
我想你矿场一半的权益…
I think half the rights to your mine
应该能偿付我们援助的费用吧
should cover the expense of our assistance.
你们的援助？
What assistance?
我们在来的路上都看到火焰
We have all seen the fires on the way here.
也知道卡瓦哈男爵和他家人的死讯
We have learned of the deaths of Baron Covasha and his family.
狼族也攻到你们的门口了
The wolves are at your door as well.
你们连自保都有问题
So why should I pay tribute
我为什么要进贡给你们？
when you cannot so much as protect your own house?
你已经把我榨乾了
You have all but bled me dry already.
我们都听说了
We have all heard the stories.
看他的眼睛! 这是真的!
Look into his eyes. They are true.
这里受到诅咒
This place is cursed.
他们不是人了
They are no more human
是魔鬼 把我们土地…
than the devils that invade our lands.
如果我们是魔鬼 放心 远比你们不知道的那些要好
If devils you call us, rest assured, better the devil you know.
- 放开我 - 当然
- Unhand me. - Certainly.
还有谁有话要说？
Would anyone else like to be heard?
把食物送给这些肮脏的狗
Toss it here. Bring food to these filthy mongrels.
- 来了 - 跟狗一样舔吧
- Here you go. - Eat it up like dogs.
跟狗一样
Like dogs.
我们不是野兽
We are not animals.
难道你们想当他们的玩具？
Is this what you want, to be their entertainment, their playthings?
当他们的宠物？
Their pets.
蜷曲在鞭子之下
Cowering beneath the whip
却在彼此之间争斗
and then fighting amongst ourselves.
这就是你们想要的？
Is this what you want?
我一辈子都在遵守规则
I have lived by their rules my entire life.
我保卫他们
I've protected them,
嫉妒他们
envied them.
结果呢？
And for what?
结果却被当成野兽对待
To be treated like an animal.
我们不是野兽
We are not animals!
我们有选择
We do have a choice.
我们可以选择比这更好的
We can choose to be more than this.
我们可以是奴隶
We can be slaves
我们也可以是狼人
or we can be Lycans!
天快亮了 我的孩子
Morning is upon us, my child.
我们该将不幸的夜置之脑后
It's time we left this wretched night behind.
- 我很乐意 - 眼前有一些困难的决策
- Gladly. - There are some difficult decisions ahead.
- 我希望你的帮助 - 当然 父亲
- I would like your help with one of them. - Of course, Father.
失去了卢西恩
With Lucian gone,
我们得提拔另一个狼人取代他
we must promote another Lycan in his place.
失去？
Gone?
科洛曼认为他会煽动其他人
Coloman thinks he will stir the others.
我们必须除掉他
We must remove him.
这很困难
That will be difficult.
他跟我们这么久了
He has been with us so long.
也许用幽格吧
Perhaps Gyorg.
或特拉斯
Or Trasos.
他们都很…
They would be
值得信赖
trustworthy.
很好的建议
Excellent suggestions.
我会仔细考虑
I will consider them strongly.
你 我的孩子 是我心中最珍贵的宝贝
You, my child, are the most precious thing in my heart.
你跟我父亲说了什么？
What have you told my father?
- 你说了什么？- 什么都没说
- What have you told him? - Nothing.
- 为什么？- 什么为什么？
- Why? - Why what?
为什么没说？
Why have you told him nothing?
你的父亲 会很高兴有人告诉他
Would your father welcome the man who brought him news
他心爱女儿的交往对象…
that his beloved daughter was consorting
是狼人吗？
with a Lycan?
他是知名的冷酷无情
He isn't well known for his gratitude.
我还不想利用这个消息 替自己谋福利
And I am not yet in a position to use this for my benefit.
什么样的福利？
What sort of benefit?
理事会的议员有十二席
There are 12 council seats.
我们又不常死人
And we don't die often.
真可惜 是啊
Sadly, no.
要是我放弃我在理事会的席位
So, what if I gave up my seat at council?
直接留给你呢？
Simply left it to you?
你为什么要那么做？
Why would you do that?
你能保守秘密吗？
Can you keep a secret?
我需要一些回报
I will need something in return.
只有两分钟
Two minutes.
再久就会有危险
Any longer is too risky.
对不起 没有其他办法
I'm sorry. There was no other way.
坦尼斯？
So Tannis?
你说的对 他想要理事会的席位
You were right. He will help us in exchange for a seat on the council.
- 而你父亲毫不知情？- 我很确定
- Your father knows nothing? - I'm sure of it.
- 索妮亚 干的漂亮 - 必须如此
- Sonja, this can work. - Lucian, it has to.
我想有些人会跟我走
I think some of the others will come with me.
- 萨巴斯、瑞思托、雷兹 - 亲爱的…
- Sabas and Xristo, the human Raze. - My love...
- 我肯定可以… - 卢西恩 没时间了
- I'm certain I can... - Lucian, there is no time.
我父亲明天等人类离开 就会处决你
My father will have you killed tomorrow, after the humans are turned.
你必须在天亮时离开
You must leave at sunrise.
- 你呢？- 重要的是你保住性命
- And you? - The important thing is you stay alive.
维克多和死亡行者入睡时 是你的好机会
The best chance you have is when Viktor and the Death Dealers sleep.
你走之后 我在父亲身边很安全
I will be safely at my father's side when you go.
快点
Hurry.
计划若成功 三天后日落时见
If this plan works, I'll meet you in three days' time, after the sun sets.
河边有个空地 我在那里等你
There's a clearing by the river. I'll meet you there.
- 不成功呢？- 我会在空地等你
- And if it doesn't? - I will meet you at the clearing.
靠墙站好!
Face the wall.
- 出来 - 你们这些野兽
- Get out. - You animals.
你! 马上回去!
You. Get back.
勇敢点 人类
Be brave, human.
你知道你有什么问题吗？
You know what your problem is?
你不明白大自然的法则
You don't understand the natural order of things.
凡事都会变
Things change.
那你可要准备好了
Be ready when they do.
把这当成临别的礼物吧
Consider it a parting gift.
等等!
Wait.
你不明白这是我给你的礼物？
Do you not realize this is a gift I am giving you?
这是诅咒!
It's a curse.
- 它们？对我们做了什么 - 你很快就会知道的
- What have they done to us? - You'll find out soon enough.
他们把我们变成…和你一样
They turned us into... Like you?
对
Yes.
为什么？
Why?
他要利用你来保护他
He wants to use you for his own protection.
我会先死
I will die first.
那可能不会发生
Well, that may not happen.
时候到了
The time has come.
天亮时 我会离开此地
At sunrise, I leave this place.
愿意冒险的人可以跟我走
Anyone willing to take the risk may follow me.
墙外有新的生活等着我们
There is a new life waiting beyond these walls, my friend,
你可以成为我们的一部分
and you can be a part of it, one of us,
或是留下来侍奉他们
or stay and serve them.
警卫来了
The guards are coming.
今天有新狗 看看他们的长相
New dogs today. Let's see how they look.
你来太晚了
You've come too late.
他已经走了
He's already gone.
你们要跟我走吗？
Are you with me?
萨巴斯、瑞思托 释放其他人 其他的跟我走
Sabas, Xristo, free the others. The rest of you with me.
你们自由了
Freedom is yours.
快走!
Move!
往这边!
This way.
下面!
Down here.
快走! 跑! 跑!
All right, move. Run, run, run.
继续跑!
Keep moving.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
继续跑!
Keep going. Move.
发射!
Fire.
雷兹!
Raze.
你无能为力了
There is nothing you can do.
我会回来的! 我保证!
I will come back. I promise you.
不!
No!
大人
My lord.
大人 卢西恩逃走了
My lord, Lucian is escaping.
往森林去! 快去!
Forest, go. Go!
大人!
My lord.
快点!
Move here. Move it.
- 你! 进去! - 快点!
- You, get in there. - Move.
- 就这些？没漏掉任何一个？- 是的
- Are all these accounted for? Each and every one. - Yes.
坦尼斯？
Tannis.
快点!
Come on. Move.
是的 大人
Yes, my lord?
我给你的钥匙在那里？
Where is the key I gave you for this?
- 我亲自把它锁在军械库的 - 那么它是怎么开的？
- I locked it in the armory myself. - How, then, is it open?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我想我知道
I think I have.
- 杀了他! - 不!
- Kill him. - No.
求求你
Please.
去看军械库
Check the armory.
一定有一个解释的
There has to be an explanation.
带我去看
Show me.
- 我从没出过城 - 趁你可以享受时享受吧
- I've never been outside the walls. - Well, enjoy it while you can, Xristo.
因为我们很快就得打回去了
Because soon enough we're gonna have to fight our way back in.
我们没全逃出来 我不会丢下弟兄…
We did not all make it out, and I will not leave our brothers to rot back there.
维克多受辱 会拿他们出气
We humiliated Viktor. It is they who will pay the cost.
不过我们很幸运能活着逃出来
But we were lucky to make it out alive.
我们人数不多 又没武器
And there's but a handful of us. We have no weapons.
目前是如此
True, for now.
你能带我们去贵族的领地吗？
The noble who brought you here, can you lead us back to his estate?
- 可以 - 好 走吧
- Yes. - Good. Come on. Come on.
一定在这里
It has to be here.
我放在这里
I put it here.
在这里
Here.
他一定还有另一把
He must have made another one.
我从未怀疑过你
I never doubted you.
现在我不想卸除你们的颈圈之后
Now, I have no wish to remove one shackle from around your necks
却铐上我对你们的箝制
only to replace it with one of my own.
你们有选择
You have a choice.
逃跑或躲藏
You can run and hide
或是留下来奋战
or you can stay and fight.
任何与我并肩作战者
Any man who fights with me shall have his freedom
如果他真的愿意的话…
and, if he wishes it,
将会享有自由和永生
immortality.
捡起你的武器
Pick up your weapons.
我们团结才能壮大
Together we're strong.
西边有其他的族人领地
There are other estates to the west of here.
我想要让你去
I want you to go there.
看有多少人要加入我们
See how many will join us.
我们两天后在此碰头
I will meet you back here in two days' time.
- 放在哪里 - 那里
- Put it over there. - Over here.
父亲
Father.
我吓到你了？对不起
Did I startle you? I'm sorry.
没有
No.
你没有
You did not.
我突然想到
It occurs to me
我一直都太粗心大意了
that I have been thoughtless.
我太沉浸于卢西恩背叛的痛苦
So deep have I been in my own anguish at Lucian's betrayal,
却完全没考虑到…
I gave no thought
你的感受
to your feelings.
我的感受？
My feelings?
他们融入我们的生活之中
They worm their way into our lives,
我们却忘了他们可笑的出世
and we forget the travesty of their birth.
我自己对卢西恩充满慈悲
I myself had tenderness towards Lucian.
他可以成就大事
He could have been anything.
也许还可以当死亡行者
A Death Dealer, perhaps.
是啊
Yes.
也许吧
Perhaps.
不过他毕竟与我们不同
But he was not as we are,
对吧？
was he?
你是否帮助他逃亡？
Did you help him escape?
帮助他？
Help him?
当然没有
Of course not.
你在骗我？
Are you lying to me?
我是做过很多违抗你的事
There are many things that I have done against your will,
可是他是狼人
but he is a Lycan.
对不起 乖女儿
I'm sorry, my dear,
你让我别无选择
but you leave me no choice.
父亲 求求你
Father, please...
我原本想相信你的谎言 虽然我知道那不是真的
I wanted to believe your lies though I knew it could not be true.
可是我的亲生女儿 你怎么能？
Not my own daughter. How could you?
父亲
Father,
我爱他
I love him.
你背叛了我
You have betrayed me!
跟野兽在一起
To be with an animal!
我爱你胜过一切
I loved you more than anything!
不准她离开房间
She does not leave this room!
不行 我们受命要等待
No. You're under orders to wait.
在这
Here.
照这速度 到周末人手就够了
This rate, we'll have enough men by the end of the week.
- 有索妮亚的消息吗？- 没有
- Has there been any sign of Sonja? - Nothing.
她应该早就到了
She should have been here by now.
卢西恩 等她并不明智
With respect, Lucian, I do not see the wisdom in waiting for her.
她不是我们的人
She's not one of us.
你忘了是她释放我们的吗？
Have you forgotten she is the one who set us free?
可是她是吸血鬼
But she is a vampire.
若她骗你 她会带他们来此
If she has deceived you, she could lead them here.
死亡行者绝对会大举出击
Death Dealers will undoubtedly be on the hunt,
他们终究会找到我们 不过不会是她告的密
and they will eventually find us, but not by her doing.
我相信索妮亚 你们也该如此
I trust Sonja with my life, and as long as I'm in command, so shall you.
就跟你说什么都别讲吧
Told you not to say anything.
卢西恩掠夺了布拉索夫的两个庄园
Lucian has sacked two estates in Brashov, my lord, and made off
还偷走了他们的军械 而奴隶们加入了他的队伍
with the contents of their armories. The slaves have joined his ranks.
自由就像威廉的瘟疫一样蔓延
Freedom is as much a disease as William's pestilence.
- 你得把你的宠物弄回来 - 谢谢 科洛曼
- You need to bring your pet back. - Thank you, Coloman.
我显然疏忽了
The obvious escaped me.
我不用动一根手指头 卢西恩会自己回来的
I do not need to lift a finger. Lucian will return of his own free will.
我有他要的东西
I have something he wants.
我的爱人
My lady.
- 露卡 怎么回事？她人呢？- 索妮亚被逮捕了
- Luka. What is it? Where is she? - Sonja has been arrested.
他知道你们的事了
He knows about the two of you.
他会杀了她
He will kill her.
我想你该知道
I thought you should know.
还没有动静 大人
Nothing yet, my lord.
- 这是陷阱 你很清楚 - 我不会让她独自死去
- It is a trap. You know that. - I will not let her die alone.
它们追随你来 你走了它们也会走
They followed you here, Lucian. If you go, we will lose them.
让我告诉你 它们以为它们是追随我而来
Let me tell you a secret, my friend. They thought they followed me.
但它们真正追随的是自由 那才是吸引它们来的原因
What they truly followed was the idea of being free. That's what brought them here.
你可以带领它们等我回来 我若没回来 则由你领导它们
Now, you can hold them together until I get back, and lead them if I do not.
- 你没事吧？- 没事
- Are you all right? - Yes.
可是卢西恩 你已经自由了
But Lucian, you were free.
没有你就不算是
Not without you.
我们得马上走
We have to go now.
大人
My lord,
您女儿逃走了
your daughter has escaped.
她当然会逃
Of course she has.
往这边!
This way.
- 那一个 - 是 大人
- That one. - Yes, sir.
就是现在!
Now.
你竟敢对抗我？
How dare you raise your hand to me?
- 我不想这样 - 我是你父亲
- I do not want this. - I am your father.
- 你以为你能打败我吗？- 我不想打败你
- Do you think you can defeat me? - I don't want to defeat you.
杀了我并不能救你的宝贝狼人
Killing me won't save your precious Lycan.
为了你的孙子 撤回你的人
Please call off your men, for the sake of your grandchild.
这是奇迹 父亲
A miracle, Father.
两条血脉的融和
A union of the bloodlines.
我诅咒你母亲生下你而死的那天
I curse the day your mother gave her life to bring you into this world.
你体内的东西
That thing inside you
是个怪物
is a monstrosity.
索妮亚!
Sonja!
都结束了
This is over.
带走他
Remove him.
你明白你干了什么好事吗？
Do you understand what you have done?
今晚不是要逮你 而是要逮他
This night was not about you. It was about him.
我原可将卢西恩交给理事会
I could have given Lucian to the council.
他们不需要知道你鲁莽的行为 不过经过这一切
They need never have known of your indiscretion, but after this,
别想了
never.
不!
No!
要是我没走 这一切都不会发生
If I had not left, none of this would have happened.
那么你就不是你了
Then you would not be who you are.
你说的对
You were right.
没有人该过这种生活
No one should live a life like this.
其他人因为你而自由了
Others are free because of you.
因为你的作为 一切已彻底改变
Things are forever changed because of what you have done.
- 不过我令你失望了 - 不
- But I have failed you. - No.
卢西恩 我亲爱的
Lucian, my love,
你没有令我失望
you have not failed me.
是我做的决定让我来到这里
The choices I made have led me here.
不是你
Not you.
你说过你愿为我承受危险
You said yourself there are risks that you were willing to take for me,
为了你我也一样
as was I for you.
为了我们
For us.
开门!
Open the door.
- 不 - 起来!
- No. - Get up.
- 不 不 - 快啊
- No. No. - Come on. Come on.
不 我会杀了你!
No. I'll kill you.
你们全部!
All of you!
被告的罪名是谋逆
The accused has committed high treason against the coven.
她与野兽往来 她帮助他们逃亡
She has consorted with animals. She has abetted in their escape.
我拯救过我族许多次
I have saved this coven many times over.
你也杀害过自己的同胞
You have killed your own kind.
你还混杂血脉
And you've commingled bloodlines,
在你体内培育出那玩意儿
resulting in the thing germinating within you.
你过去的一切也无法补偿你造下的罪孽
Your past glory does not excuse your present guilt,
鉴于你是理事会成员
nor does your station as a council member.
显然你的惩罚应该是死刑
The punishment for these crimes is death.
但是我们投票表决
How vote you?
赞成
Aye.
- 赞成 - 赞成
- Aye. - Aye.
她是你女儿
She's your daughter.
赞成
Aye.
带她去死刑室
Take her to the chamber.
不 你们不能这么做
No, you... You cannot do this.
跟我们来
My lady, come with us.
- 请保持安静 - 求你了 维克多!
- Come quietly, - please. Viktor.
维克多! 不!
Viktor. No!
No, Viktor!
不!
No.
卢西恩
Lucian.
不 索妮亚
No, Sonja.
不要 看着我
Don't. Just look at me.
眼睛看着我 索妮亚
Keep your eyes on me, Sonja.
看着我!
Look at me!
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
As I love you.
等一切结束 你就不在了 是吧？
Your face will not be here when this is over, will it?
再见了 我的爱
Goodbye, my love.
不
No.
No!
索妮亚!
Sonja!
- 去拿我的刀 - 是 大人
- Fetch my knives. - Yes, my lord.
大人
My lord.
快去…
Go. Go. Quickly. Go.
去放其他人 快去
Now go free the others. Go!
跟我来
Follow me.
- 你们想复仇吗？- 想!
- Do you want your revenge? - Yeah.
就在外面 去吧
It is out there. Now go.
我们有比卷轴更重要的东西
We have greater concerns than your precious scrolls.
快去找长老! 快!
Go to the elders, now!
杀光这些野狗!
Kill the dogs!
维克多
Viktor.
你玷污了我女儿
You defiled my daughter.
- 我爱她 - 你害死了她
- I loved her! - You killed her!
你出生那天我就该杀了你
I should have crushed you under my heel the day you were born.
是啊 你是应该
Yes, you should have...
可是你没有
but you didn't.
卢西恩
Lucian!
Lucian.
卢西恩
都结束了
It is finished.
不
No.
一切才刚开始
This is just the beginning.
让我告诉你 你所深爱的黑暗之父
But let me tell you a little something about your beloved dark father.
他才是害死你家人的凶手 不是狼人
He's the one who killed your family. Not the Lycans.
不过当他看到你
But when he got to you,
他却不忍心有吸乾你血的想法
he just couldn't bear the thought of draining you dry.
你...让他回忆起了心爱的索妮亚
You, who reminded him so much of his precious Sonja,
他亲自处决的女儿
the daughter he condemned to death.
一派胡言
Lies.